Inventory of the Mills E. Godwin Jr. Papers 1947-1989
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Accession 1994.66, 1981-1992., ca. 2,070 items. (Box 1-4)
  - General Papers and Letters, 1981-1992. (Box 1-2)
    - General papers and letters, 1 June 1988-15 December 1988., 33 items. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Items concern personal letters; correspondence concerning Hope Spivey, a gymnast from Godwin's hometown; and letters of concern relating to Godwin's hospitalization.
    - General papers and letters, 1 January 1989-12 July 1989., 39 items. (Box-folder 2:6)
      Items include personal letters, letters regarding personal business transactions.
    - General papers and letters, 18 July 1989-6 December 1989., 34 items. (Box-folder 2:7)
      Items include personal letters concerning business transactions, a letter regarding the Chesapeake Bay Bridge and Tunnel, and letters concerning the death of Carter Lowance.
    - General papers and letters, 2 January 1990-20 June 1990., 42 items. (Box-folder 2:8)
      Item include personal letters, and letters regarding personal business transactions.
    - General papers and letters, 25 June 1990-19 December 1990, n.d., 41 items. (Box-folder 2:9)
      Items include personal letters, and letters regarding personal business transactions.
    - General papers and letters, 28 December 1990-7 August 1991., 23 items. (Box-folder 2:10)
    - General papers and letters, 9 August 1991-27 December 1991., 22 items. (Box-folder 2:11)
    - General papers and letters, 15 January 1992-30 December 1992., 43 items. (Box-folder 2:12)
      Items include information about a west Norfolk, Virginia tract of industrial property, personal letters, and letters regarding personal business transactions.
  - GOP, 1988-1992. (Box-folder 2:13-16)
    - GOP, 12 January 1988-15 November 1989., 25 items. (Box-folder 2:13)
      Items include an essay on the "Reagan legacy," a newsletter devoted to '88 presidential election in Virginia, editorials, letters concerning campaigns, a biographical sketch of Howard Worth Smith, letters to and from Godwin regarding functions, campaign strategy, etc., roster of committee chairpersons for Virginia Republican Party (1989), and letters and papers about various other facets of Virginia Republican politics.
    - GOP, 6 January 1992-22 May 1992., 39 items. (Box-folder 2:14)
      Items include invitations for fun raising functions, news clippings, letters to and from George Allen, a letter from Harry F. Byrd, letter to Godwin asking for his support of Pat Buchanan, letter from John Warner, and other letters dealing with GOP races in 1992.
    - GOP, 23 May 1992-18 August 1992., 25 items. (Box-folder 2:15)
      Items include letters to and from Davis Paschall and Pat Robertson, letters and newsletters from the Suffolk Republican Party headquarters, and an article from The Sun about young Republican volunteers.
    - GOP, 12 October 1992-7 December 1992, n.d., 26 items. (Box-folder 2:16)
      Items include fund raising letters, news clippings and editorials, a letter from Harry F. Byrd with enclosed editorial, letters from the Republican National Committee, a letter from Dan Quayle, card from George Bush, news clipping about Charles Robb, and other papers relating to GOP contests in 1992.
  - Governor's Office, 23 May 1978-15 April 1991., 29 items. (Box-folder 2:17)
    Items include a copy of the 1978 joint resolution about the Harry F. Byrd Memorial Commission, and letters from John Dalton and Charles Robb.
  - Greater Hampton Roads Organization, 14 May 1980-3 October 1983, n.d., 31 items. (Box-folder 2:18)
    Items include financial statements from June 1981, letters (business and personal), a letter to Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr., a report, "Invest in America's Cities" from U. S. Conference of Mayor's Conference in Zurich, Switzerland, and other papers.
  - Higher Education, 3 January 1978-28 April 1979, n.d., 57 items. (Box-folder 2:19)
    Item include the HEW controversy: editorials, news clippings, and letters relating to Virginia desegregation efforts and HEW directives regarding such efforts.
  - Invitations Declined, 1989-1992. (Box 2-3)
    - Invitations Declined, 23 January 1989-20 April 1989., 28 items. (Box-folder 2:20)
      Items include invitations and letters of regret.
    - Invitations Declined, 24 April 1989-21 September 1989., 27 items. (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Invitations Declined, 21 September 1989-18 December 1989., 21 items. (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Invitations Declined, 20 December 1990-24 October 1991., 44 items. (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Invitations Declined, 24 October 1991-5 June 1992, n.d., 31 items. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Invitations Declined, 18 June 1992-23 December 1992., 27 items. (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 1988-1992. (Box-folder 3:6-8)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 5 July 1985-27 July 1988., 36 items. (Box-folder 3:6)
      Items include letters to and from Godwin about his membership on the Board of Directors, financial report from December 1985, various papers about Foundation business, and financial statements for 1986.
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 5 July 1985-27 July 1988., 22 items. (Box-folder 3:7)
      Items include 1989 Annual Report for Development Program for Jamestown-Yorktown Educational Trust, newsletters from Jamestown-Yorktown Educational Trust, and other papers.
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 5 July 1985-27 July 1988., 25 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
      Items include letters concerning Jamestown-Yorktown Educational Trust, letters concerning the opening of the Jamestown Settlement Galleries, and letters regarding various other functions.
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation, 1 January 1990-18 September 1992., 7 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
    Items include a list of trustees, pamphlet about the Monticello cabinet, and magazine article about the roof of Monticello.
  - Lottery in Virginia, 31 December 1986-5 November 1987., 42 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
    Items include letters and copies of speeches in opposition to the proposed lottery in 1987.
  - Miscellaneous, 1949, 1977-1986, n.d., 37 items. (Box-folder 3:11)
    Items include a program from the Boy Scout meeting of 28 April 1949, personal letters, photographs, letter from president of University of Virginia, legal papers, and a copy of the Suffolk newspaper with an article about Virginia's Community Colleges.
  - Personal Papers, 1980-1988. (Box-folder 3:12-14)
    - Personal Papers, 10 January 1980-21 August 1986., 49 items. (Box-folder 3:12)
      Items include personal letters, letters concerning personal business transactions, invitation to the first inaugural of Ronald Reagan, correspondence regarding proposed magazine advertisement featuring Godwin, correspondence between Godwin and William and Mary College Republicans, letters concerning awards and honors, correspondence regarding Federal appointment of Godwin by President Nixon, and correspondence between Godwin and former William and Mary president Davis Paschall.
    - Personal Papers, 7 October 1986-4 January 1988., 30 items. (Box-folder 3:13)
      Items include personal letters, letters regarding personal business transactions, correspondence regarding the book Suffolk: A Pictorial History and Godwin's foreword to the text.
    - Personal Papers, 7 January 1988-31 December 1988., 43 items. (Box-folder 3:14)
      Items include personal letters, letters concerning personal business transactions, newspaper editorial with reference to Godwin, correspondence between Godwin and Mrs. Pitonyak's fourth grade class, newspaper article about the Governor's Mansion, and a list of buildings in Virginia named after Godwin.
  - Political Papers, 1989-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 3:15-17)
    - Political Papers, 3 January 1989-6 December 1989., 26 items. (Box-folder 3:15)
      Items include letters to and from Virginia politicians, articles about Judge Willard H. Douglas, Jr., and a letter from Richard T. Short with enclosed letters to prominent politicians (e.g., Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Strom Thurmond, Jesse Helms.
    - Political Papers, 3 January 1990-7 November 1991., 32 items. (Box-folder 3:16)
      Items include letters to and from Godwin regarding Virginia politics, including correspondence with Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Albertis Harrison, Hunter Andrews, and Davis Paschall.
    - Political Papers, 4 December 1991-21 December 1992, n.d., 25 items. (Box-folder 3:17)
      Items include news clippings, editorials, photograph of President and Mrs. Bush, photograph of Teddy Roosevelt in the Panama Canal, correspondence with Richard Short, Pat Buchanan, Davis Paschall and others. Also included is the Times-Dispatch editorial on the 1992 L.A. riots and letter of reaction from Godwin.
  - Transportation Commission, 25 March 1986-24 September 1987., 29 items. (Box-folder 3:18)
    Items include letters, official papers, and news clippings concerning the 1986-87 Governor's Commission on Transportation. Also included are comments by former Governor Albertis S. Harrison.
  - Transportation Commission, 7 December 1987-6 January 1988, n.d., 18 items. (Box-folder 3:19)
    Items include the December 1987 Report of the Local Financing Options Subcommittee, letter of thanks to Godwin from Governor Baliles, draft of the final report, news clippings, roster of Commission members, copy of remarks made by Godwin concerning his reservations about the final report.
  - Trible, Paul (Campaign for Governor 1989), 11 November 1988-26 June 1989, n.d., 31 items. (Box-folder 3:20)
    Items include letters written to Godwin in support of Trible, campaign newsletters, newspaper articles about Godwin's endorsement of Trible, and Godwin's letter announcing endorsement.
  - Virginia Cultural Laureate Society, 14 May 1987-23 March 1988., 20 items. (Box-folder 3:21)
    Items include invitations to meetings and ceremonies, and letters concerning affairs of the society.
  - Virginia - General Papers, 27 October 1987-6 March 1991., 21 items. (Box-folder 4:1)
    Items include letters concerning Virginia's international trade, the State Water Authority, the Virginia State Library, an invitation to the 1990 inauguration of Douglas Wilder, and a letter from the William and Mary School of Business Administration.
  - Virginia - General Papers, 11 March 1991-1 October 1992., 15 items. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Items include correspondence between Governor Godwin and various state senators, a copy of speech given by Frances Hallam Hurt in support of state arts program, a letter from Lio Bourassa expressing concern about Virginia water problems, the 1991 Report of the Secretary of Finance on Virginia's financial situation, and miscellaneous letters.
  - Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges, 1987-1992. (Box-folder 4:3-6)
    - Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges, 21 July 1986-4 August 1987., 34 items. (Box-folder 4:3)
      Items include letters pertaining to finances and business of the Foundation as well as personal letters.
    - Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges, 4 August 1987-22 December 1988., 37 items. (Box-folder 4:4)
      Items include letters pertaining to business and finances of Foundation as well as personal letters.
    - Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges, 10 January 1989-20 December 1989., 27 items. (Box-folder 4:5)
      Items include business and personal letters concerning affairs of the Foundation.
    - Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges, 20 December 1989-18 December 1992., 50 items. (Box-folder 4:6)
      Items include business and personal letters.
  - Virginia Wesleyan College, 18 January 1991-24 November 1992, n.d., 46 items. (Box-folder 4:7)
    Items include official papers, letters and memoranda concerning affairs of the college.